

Frank Gaete

- frank.gaete1@gmail.com
- in linkedin.com/in/frankgaete/
- ttps://vanhalen1.github.io/FGaete/

Summary

I am a UI/UX designer with over 26 years of experience across numerous verticals and organizations ranging from small startups to global fortune 500. I strongly advocate user centered design, UX research, cross team collaboration; design consistency, and delivery of optimized user experiences.

Work Experience

TD Bank, Sr. UX Designer

Aug 2021 – present, Remote

- Design interfaces and experiences for client facing products and services
- Develop wireframes, visual designs, user flows/journeys using Figma, Adobe XD
- Plan and design UX research goals and prototypes; analyze data to guide design enhancement recommendations
- Collaborate with pod members (PO, scrum master, devs, QA, content and others); cross team members and enterprise UX designers to ensure consistency across products and platforms

NextEra/Florida Power & Light, Sr. UX Design & Research

Jan 2020 – Jul 2021, Jupiter FL

- Designed interfaces and experiences for nuclear power enterprise applications
- Planned and executed UX research; analyze data to guide design enhancement recommendations; help standardize UX research methods and processes for future testing
- Developed new design patterns and workflows using Adobe XD, Sketch, and UXpin
- Collaborated with nuclear team members; product owners and enterprise UX designers

Clever Devices, Sr. UX Architect

Sep 2017 – Dec 2019, Woodbury NY

- Designed interfaces and experiences across several major product groups for desktop, responsive and mobile applications as per requirements, business goals and user research
- Promoted the value of UX research; defined and executed research processes and methodologies to drive design enhancement recommendations
- Designed and defined pattern libraries, style guides, UI/UX policies; software and hardware recommendations
- Collaborated with various teams to ensure consistency across products and corporate communications

Experience 2020 - 1997

- Valiant Solutions Director UI/UX, Woodbury NY
- Broadridge Financial Solutions Lead UI/UX Architect, Edgewood NY
- CA Technologies Web Developer, Islandia NY
- The Creative Group Web Designer/Developer, Rockville Center NY
- Veritas Laboratories Senior Designer / Developer / Project Manager, Bohemia NY
- Dowling College: Web Services Administrator, Oakdale NY
- theglobe.com Web Producer/Developer, Manhattan NY
- Channel21 Productions Webmaster/Technical Manager, Miller Place NY

References

Education

B.A. Social Science

Adelphi University, Garden City

Certificate

Internet Architecture at Hofstra University, Uniondale

Certificate

Client Server Systems at Dowling College, Oakdale

Skills

UI/UX Design
PC/Mac
Adobe XD, Creative Suite
Figma
UX Research

HTML, CSS
Ideation, collaboration
Agile, Jira

Military Experience

US Army Reserve. Highest Rank: Sergeant. Honorable Discharge

Interests

Tennis

Guitar

Movies, music

Travel

Boating

Family & friends

Available upon request